# Ali Ataf

### Frontend Engineer

A Software Engineer with over 3 years of experience in frontend development with a passion for building and maintaining responsive, accessible, and performant websites. I have worked with technologies, including HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Angular, Vue, RxJS, React, Next.js and Tailwindcss.

aliattaf98@gmail.com

+971 50 235 7409

Dubai, UAE

aliataf.com

linkedin.com/in/ali-ataf

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

# Frontend Engineer

Supy 2

03/2022 - Present

Dubai, UAE

### Frontend Developer

Nestech 🗷

09/2021 - 02/2022

Svria (Remote)

- Worked directly with UI/UX designer and converted the designs she gave me to fast front-end web applications.
- Engaged in daily scrum meetings with our five members team to optimize the development process.
- Finished 5+ web applications with a responsive mobilefirst approach from concept to deployment.

# Frontend Developer

BadinanSoft 🗷

04/2021 - 09/2021

Iraq (Remote)

- Established testing and modular coding development environment for company projects.
- Enhanced legacy projects UX by implementing the right technologies and fixing UI bugs.
- Helped the project manager to organize the team's tasks using Jira software.

# Frontend Developer

Unifi Solutions 🗷

11/2020 - 04/2021

Montreal, QC (Remote)

- Led the development process of the "BACT" system.
- Automated the injecting of state and routing modules using JS scripts.
- Maintained scalable system-wide components that were used in the IoT web application.

# **Junior Frontend Developer**

Zeuor 🗷

09/2019 - 11/2020

- Built web applications for Queue Management System.
- Reduced load time by over 60% by dropping ¡Query UI and re-writing all CSS from scratch.
- Implemented visual designs that are user-friendly.

#### **EDUCATION**

# **Bachelor of Software Engineering** Tishreen University

09/2016 - 09/2021 (GPA: 3.4 / 4.0)

# **SKILLS**



## **PROJECTS**

Tasqment (09/2020 - 09/2021) 🗹

- Transformed the design of the application into a well-structured web application.
- Implemented SSO, 2fa, and chat system in the project.
- Deployed the app on digitalocean droplet and set the server up dealing with all related server issues.
- Stack: Vue.js, Element UI, Vuex, SortableJS, PHP, Laravel, Dart, Flutter, Firebase, Pusher.

#### DisruptX IoT (01/2021 - 04/2021) 🗗

- Developed responsive email templates across various email clients using table layout and inline styles.
- Participated in the system structure decisions and contributed to the modular structure used in the application.
- Worked closely with designers and product owners to translate clients' requirements into scalable web applications.
- Stack: Vue.js, Quasar, Vuex, Node.js, Express.

#### BACT learning system (11/2020 - 01/2021) 🗹

- Designed, analyzed, and broke down the requirements into categorized tasks with priorities.
- Handled all requirements changes working in an agile methodology.
- Translated designs into reusable UI components.
- Stack: Vue.js, Vuetify, Vuex.

#### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

Won 3rd place in Tamayuz competition

Participated in the "Encouraging Arabic content to use digital transformation tools" category.

#### **LANGUAGES**

Arabic

English

Native or Bilingual Proficiency Full Professional Proficiency

#### **INTERESTS**

Chess Reading

Music